aflcio.org 2004-12-20

# Privacy Policy

The AFL-CIO has created this privacy notice to explain how we use information that you may provide while visiting our website and to demonstrate our firm commitment to Internet privacy. The AFL-CIO may modify this policy from time to time so we encourage you to check this page when revisiting this website. 

The following discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for this website. The type and amount of information received depends on how you use the site. 

**Website Usage/Information Collection  
** When you visit the AFL-CIO website, we automatically obtain information from you about the name of your Internet service provider, the browser and type of computer you are using, the website that referred you to us, the pages you request and the date and time of those requests. We use this information on an aggregate basis to generate statistics and measure site activity to improve the usefulness of the site to our visitors. For example, we use this information to track which pages are most popular among visitors as a whole. We do not track the pages you or any individual visitor may look at during a visit to our site and we do not collect any other information without your knowledge and permission. We do not collect or store personally identifiable information, such as your name, mailing address, e-mail address or phone number, unless you provide that information. 

**Collection of Personally Identifiable Information  
** The AFL-CIO provides Web forms so you may provide your contact information to engage in AFL-CIO activities such as online activism (i.e., contact Congress), to place orders for products or services, to correspond with the AFL-CIO or to submit a testimonial (i.e., share your story). Any information we collect, such as your name, mailing address, e-mail address, type of request you are making and any additional information you provide, is collected and stored by the AFL-CIO. The information is used to fulfill your request and track aggregate information about usage of these features. The AFL-CIO makes every effort to ensure the secure collection and transmission of your sensitive information using industry accepted data collection and encryption methodologies, such as SSL (Secure Sockets Layer). 

**SPECIAL NOTICE FOR PARENTS:  
** We want to help you guard your children's privacy. We encourage you to talk to your children about safe and responsible use of their personal information while using the Internet. The AFL-CIO does not collect, use or distribute children's personally identifiable information to any third parties. If you have any reservations, questions or concerns about your child's access to this site or how information that your child provides is used by us, please contact us. 

**AFL-CIO's Sharing of Personally Identifiable Information  
** The AFL-CIO may exchange limited personally identifiable information (such as name and e-mail address) with partner organizations when people join as dues-paying members of an affiliate union of the AFL-CIO or the Alliance for Retired Americans and become part of that organization's regular membership list. 

The AFL-CIO website will not post your personal contact information, including e-mail address, street address and phone numbers, without your consent. Without such consent, website staff will withhold posting personal contact information for that individual.

**Financial Information and Payments  
** We use a secure server for processing payments and financial information. AFL-CIO staff log in to the secure site, retrieve the information and process it using our in-house credit card processing equipment. The AFL-CIO does not retain, share, store or use personally identifiable information for any secondary purposes. 

**Cookies  
** A cookie is a piece of data stored on the user's hard drive containing information about the user. The AFL-CIO website uses a cookie for measuring aggregate web statistics, including number of monthly visitors, number of repeat visitors, most popular webpages and other information. AFL-CIO will also use cookies to facilitate your online visit by maintaining data that you provide for online activism activities so that you will not need to resubmit certain information. The AFL-CIO does not use cookies to track what specific pages an individual site visitor views. 

**Opting Out of E-mail Lists  
** People who subscribe to e-mail lists via the website will receive periodic updates from the AFL-CIO by regular mail, fax or e-mail. You may opt out of receiving future information via e-mail by using the unsubscribe procedure specified on the e-mail message or by sending an e-mail message with the name of the list you are a member of to: feedback@aflcio.org.

**Outside Links  
** This site contains hypertext links to other sites. The AFL-CIO is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such websites. We encourage our users to be aware when they leave our site, and to read the privacy statements of each and every website that collects personally identifiable information. This privacy statement applies solely to information collected by this website.

**Security  
**  
This site has security measures in place to protect the loss, misuse and alteration of the information under our control. We use Secure Socket Layer (SSL) encryption to protect the transmission of information you submit to us when you use our secure online forms. You are on a secure page when the lock icon on the bottom of Web browsers such as Netscape Navigator and Microsoft Internet Explorer become locked, as opposed to un-locked, or open, when you are just "surfing." All the information you provide us through these forms is stored securely off-line. 

We use SSL encryption to protect sensitive information online, we also protect user information off-line. All user information is restricted in our offices. Only employees who need information to perform a specific job (e.g., our billing clerk or a customer service representative) are granted access to personally identifiable information. All employees are kept up-to-date on our security and privacy practices. Finally, the servers that store sensitive information are kept in a secure environment.

If you send us an e-mail, you should know that e-mail is not necessarily secure against interception. So, if your communication includes sensitive information like your bank account, charge card, or social security number, and you prefer not to use one of our secure online complaint forms, contact us by mail or by telephone rather than by e-mail.

**Corrections/Updating Personal Information:**  
If your personal information changes (such as your ZIP code), or if you wish to have your information removed from our database, contact us and we will endeavor to provide a way to correct, update or remove that personal data provided to us.

**Contact Us**  
If you experience technical problems with the operation of this website, contact us by e-mailing: feedback@aflcio.org.

www.aflcio.org  
AFL-CIO Web Editor  
815 16th St., N.W.  
Washington, DC 20006  
202-637-5000

You also may contact us by mail or telephone. If you do so, we may use the information you provide in the ways we have described in this privacy policy.

September 4, 2001
